How do you know?
你又怎么知道（是这样的）呢
This is a big question.
这是个大问题
Here it says, “Hṛdayenābhyanu jñāto”— [Ms: 2.1]
（梵文）
the heart will know.
你的心知道
[Sincerity is Invincible]
心诚所至 金石为开
So on the check-list we’re seeing:
我们知道有
‘the revealed truth’, ‘living interpretation’,
揭示的真理，活生生的解读等等
But then how do you know?
但你怎么知道（他们说的是对的呢）？
He’s saying, “Your heart will recognise that.”
你的心会识别出
And then you say, “What if I’m wrong?
你又说了“万一我错了呢？
Sometimes my heart was …
有时候我的心也不太...
I thought about some particular relationship
我原本以为上段感情
that the heart is supposed to know about,
我的心应该明白是怎么回事
and it was wrong— I was wrong.
但我却错了
I’ve lived and learned to say, “I was wrong;
生活的经验教会我，我错了
my heart was deceived, or I deceived myself, I’m not sure.
我的心被骗了，还是我骗了自己，这不好说
So I don’t want this to happen for this type of choice.”
所以在这灵性方面，我不想再这样犯错。”
So what are we left with is our sincerity.
我们还有的是诚心
Kṛṣṇa and Arjuna have a similar conversation in Bhagavad-gītā,
在《薄伽梵歌》中Krishna跟阿尔诸那有场相似的对话
and Arjuna’s wondering,
阿尔诸那一直犹豫不决
not only [about] some of the things that you’ve said,
不仅是你刚刚说的那些事情
but he’s thinking, “What about also,
他想了“如果
I dedicate myself to this, I pursue this,
我付出了全心去追求灵性
and I don’t achieve perfection.
却达不到完美境界那怎么办？
Then all that time I could have been cultivating my mundane life,
那些精力时间原本可以用来建立我的世俗生活
I put all that time and energy in spiritual cultivation,
但都用在了灵性成长上
but I didn’t achieve perfection there—
却并没有达成完美的结果
it seems like I lose out in both worlds.”
是不是在这个两个世界我都失败了。”
And in famous śloka Kṛṣṇa says,
Krishna回答到
na hi kalyāṇa–kṛt kaśchid durgatiḿ tāta gachchhati [Bg: 6.40]
（梵文）
He said, “That which is kalyāṇa,”
Kalyana(梵文)
kalyāṇa means ‘auspicious’,
kalyana指吉祥的
or as I said before, ‘ultimately beneficial’—
我之前也说过，“最终极的福祉”
He’s saying, “To whatever degree you get involved in this,
无论你融入灵性活动中有多少
it’s good for you permanently.
都将为你带来永恒的益处
Whereas, even materially, if you cultivate something perfectly,
相反，就算物质世界里你获得了一些事物
it will be taken away from you or you will vanish.
那也将会被从你身边带走，又或者你最后会死的
One or the other is going to happen.”
总会发生的
Guru Mahārāj, he expressed it, he rendered it in his own way,
Guru Maharaj这么解释说
sort of condensed it and paraphrased it,
他凝练地说
and this is the key point:
他说关键是
he would say, “Sincerity is invincible.”
“心诚所至，金石为开”
If you are sincere, you’ll be victorious.
若够心诚，定能获胜
If I am sincere, if I do not deceive myself,
如果我够心诚，如果我不欺骗自己
then no one can deceive me.
那么没人能欺骗我
Because, we’re told, “Well, we should be careful.”
我们被告诫说“我们应该小心”
“Yes, we should be careful,” he’s saying,
“确实我们要小心”
“but who you really need to be careful about is you.”
“不过，你真正需要小心的是你自己”
So, he said, “If I …”
他解释说
Because I, me, we
因为我，我们都是
have a strong tendency towards self–deception—
有很强烈的自我欺骗倾向
that’s why we’re here;
所以才会落到这个世界里
we deceived ourselves.
我们自欺欺人
You say, “Well, why did we come ...?”
你又问了“我们为何要来到这个世界？”
You deceived yourself. I deceived myself.
你骗了自己，我骗了自己
We already made …
我们都已经
We’re here on account of bad choices,
做了错误的选择才来到这里
so when it comes to this all-important choice,
所以涉及所有这些重要的选择时
we don’t want to be wrong.
我们不想犯错
But can we then say,
但能否是
“I’m going to eliminate my free will and choice, and just …
“我能不能撤除我的自由意志和选择权，
someone else will make that choice for me?”
让别人替我做选择？”
It can’t be that way.
这不行
So it means we have to hear from the Vaiṣṇavas, hear the Scriptures.
而是说，我们必须要听从经典的建议
Someone’s particular representation
听从外士那瓦的引导，他们的话
will sympathetically vibrate in our heart,
给我们的心带来触动
and with a bowed head and folded palms
我们双手合十，俯首臣服
we’ll make a choice
而做出选择
and under the guidance of others, too, who are reliable.
在那些可靠的人的引导下
You know, we’re not beyond consulting with others.
确实，我们未到不需要请教的阶段
But ultimately it’s a personal choice that you have to make,
但最后，这还是你的个人选择
and Guru Mahārāj is saying, “If you’re sincere, you’ll be all right.”
Guru Maharaj说，“如果心够诚恳，那你就没问题”
So it’s in your hands: what you will do, whom you will choose.
因此，这是你的决定：做什么，选择谁